Everyone is talking about Harness
Engineering. Have you wondered what that
is? I'm going to explain everything.
Harness Engineering is in fact a whole
bunch of things and one of them is a bit
spooky and I'm going to take you through
it all in just a second. But first, I
want to show you the results of running
a project in an agent Harness which used
Kimmy K3 and also used the new Quen 3.8
Max. This shows the usage of the two
models, a total spend of $8.71
and let me show you what it did. For
this project, I brought back one of my
favorites. It is the CRM platform asking
a coding agent to build a sales CRM like
a Salesforce or a Pipedrive. Build the
whole thing from scratch for me to use a
personal CRM and this is what it came up
with and I have to tell you that this
is, I think, the best one I've had so
far. You're seeing here a really nice
dashboard that you land on when you
first come to the product. It's got
expected revenue as well as full revenue
based on the pipeline. It's got similar
charts if you've seen the ones I did
before like with GLM and also with
Fable. You'll also see there's this
pipeline by stage which shows new,
qualified, proposed, negotiated, won and
lost and it's showing both the total
value and the expected revenue which is
probability weighted. So, it's some
really interesting functionality that
you might see in higher end sales
platforms and then as before, the to-do
lists. It's a nice product and we can
click around and see things like the
organizations as usual, all the
functionality you'd expect, the
contacts, there's the buttons to delete
and edit, the deals with all the details
of different deals and then of course
the pipeline which is where we have a
Kanban board that also supports us being
able to drag and drop and the totals
change. Everything is working really
nicely. It's a great product. It was
built in about the same time that it
took to build it with Fable but at a
fraction of the price. Okay, so what is
harness engineering? What's it have to
do with the project I just showed you?
And what's the big deal? What's this
spooky thing I mentioned before? Let me
now reveal all. But first, don't hate me
if I give you the definition of an AI
agent one more time. An agent is an LLM
that's been equipped with tools and it's
running in a loop in order to achieve a
goal. That's the definition of an agent.
And another way you sometimes hear this
explained is that an agent is an LLM
that's in a harness. A harness is a
thing that equips it with tools, puts it
in a loop, and is oriented around
achieving a goal, repeatedly calling it
until it decides that the goal is met.
So you can think of the harness as the
scaffolding built around the LLM to
allow it to achieve more complex goals.
So we've all been on this journey for
the last few years. A couple of years
ago, the big thing was prompt
engineering. People were paid huge
amounts of money to be prompt engineers.
And then last year this new term came
along, context engineering, which is the
practice of assembling the perfect input
context to send to an agent so it'll be
best positioned for successful outcomes.
That was context engineering. But now
context engineering is old hat. We've
moved on from there. It's now all about
harness engineering. Harness
engineering, which is basically context
engineering and a whole lot more. It's
about putting together all of the
scaffolding, all of the harness that
goes around your LLM, around your agent,
to allow it to take on the hardest
possible tasks and have the best
possible outcomes. So I'm going to
explain what harness engineering is all
about and then we're going to look at
doing some harness engineering that's
going to allow us to achieve the best
sales CRM so far. So what what's in
harness engineering? So obviously the
first part of harness engineering, of
getting the right scaffolding, is doing
everything we're already doing around
context engineering, thinking about the
prompts, the tools, the memory that
we're equipping an LLM with in order to
achieve a goal. That's a big part of it.
And next up is the workflow or the loop.
It may be just as simple as going
through a to-do list or there might be
something more sophisticated about how
you want to work at a particular
problem, and we'll get concrete on that
in a second. Another point is the state,
and often with coding agents
particularly, state is managed using
markdown files by recording information
in markdown files that allows you to
track state in a persistent way, but
there are other ways as well. And then
sub agent, something that I've used
before, which is can be so powerful, it
can also be complicated if not used
well. And then agent teams, a cloud
agent teams, is more collaborative,
another way of breaking down your tasks
into different agent loops that run
independently. That's also part of
harness engineering. And then having the
right permissions, potentially running
in a sandbox to control what an agent is
able to do. And then observability,
being able to watch what's going on and
being able to evaluate it. You know how
much I go on about evaluations, so
important. That is also part of harness
engineering. Giving your model the
ability to quantitatively evaluate its
own results so that it can improve on
them. Such an an easy way to get better
outcomes from coding agents, as we saw
in my last video on the Groove Box, if
you haven't seen that. That is
observability and evaluations. And then
last but not least, self-improvement.
Self-improvement is about building
features into your agent harness so that
it's able to evolve itself. It's able to
change the agent harness and get better
and better at solving harder problems.
That's self-improvement. Now, there's
one part of self-improvement, a
particular technique within
self-improvement, that's pretty spooky.
And I'm not going to tell you right now,
I'm going to show it to you later, and I
think you'll agree that's something
that's that's quite an eye-opener. We
will get onto that. Now, some of these
just come out of the box with agent
products that you might be using. So,
like if you use Hermes, then it
basically has all of these. It's like
the Hermes feature list right here, as
we discovered when we did it in a
previous video. If you're using
something like Claude code or open code,
then you get some of this list, but some
of it is up to you. So, how you handle
state in markdown files, or how you
handle sandboxing, do you set that up?
Do you have self-improvement built into
your process? That's really up to you,
and configuring that, well, that's an
activity, and the activity is called
harness engineering. And now, I have set
up a simple project to build a CRM, and
I've incorporated many aspects of
harness engineering to show you
firsthand. And even if you don't
particularly want to dive into code, you
don't need to. It's going to be crystal
clear everything I'm doing, and how it
sets up our agent harness. Let me show
you. The first on my list after contacts
engineering was workflow. And let me
show you here, there's a file called
process.md,
and it gives a build process, basically
a workflow that we're asking for in
order to build this project. Build the
entire project as documented in the
requirements. Ensure success criteria
are met. Use a sub-agent to check the
final product. Incorporate any changes,
and then follow the instructions in
self-improve to improve yourself. We
will come back to that, but this shows
the workflow laid out. Now, I'm going to
be using open code today, and for open
code, there's a JSON file called open
code.json that describes the different
sub-agents. And this is how I've set up
my sub-agent team. I have a primary
agent that's instructed to follow the
process in process.md that we were just
looking at to build the project and
improve yourself. and it's going to be
using Qwen 3.8 max. And then we have a
product review sub-agent that tries out
the product and provides feedback, and
we'll be using Kimiko 3 for this, and
they've been set up with the appropriate
permissions so that, for example, the
reviewer is not able to change any
files. It just has to take care of its
review. And obviously, it's also through
this review that I'm able to have a kind
of evaluation of what's happening and
make sure there's a feedback loop to get
better. And then, when it comes to
sandboxing, I'm using dev container, the
functionality built into VS Code so that
it can run in an isolated Docker
container, and I've got the instructions
here that sets it up and configures it
so that it installs open code, and it
also installs a skill in the form of the
agent browser skill from Vercel so that
it's able to test its own work. And
then, last but not least, the
self-improve. So, this is where I've
added to my workflow this idea that the
harness needs to be able to improve
itself. So, when I open this, it says,
"You must complete the step, look back
at your work in building the project,
including any challenges you encountered
and the feedback, and then update your
own process, update its workflow to
factor in the learnings so that it does
better next time." This is
self-improvement in action. When this
runs, not only will it build a CRM, but
it's also going to update its own
process. So, it'll be able to build
similar things in the future better.
Okay, and now for the spooky one. Now
for the weird one. Look at step four.
This is what's known as recursive
self-improvement, and some people don't
fully appreciate what this means, but
it's explained right here. Update this
very file, self-improve.md,
so that you are more effective at
improving yourself in the future.
Improve the way you improve yourself.
Get better at getting better. That's the
idea of recursive self-improvement. We
want it not only to improve its own
process, but to improve the way that it
improves its process. That's crazy. And
so all of these activities, setting up
sub-agents, putting in place a sandbox,
having a process, having a feedback
evaluation loop with a sub-agent, and
then having this improvement, this
self-improvement, and even recursive
self- improvement step. This is all what
goes into harness engineering. That's
what I've done, and now it's time to put
it into action. And so now here I am
inside a dev container, and I'm going to
type open code to launch open code. Here
it is. And now I'm going to press shift
tab to flip over to my build and improve
primary agent, and we're ready to go.
And I'm just going to say to it like,
"Go ahead, build the project, improve
yourself. Do do your business. Let's see
what it does." It's using Qwen 3.8 max.
It's looking around at what files it can
access, and it's going to go off and do
its thing, and I will see you in a
minute. All right, so it's not exactly
been a minute. It's been like an hour,
an hour and a half. I've gone and had
lunch, but here are the results. You can
see that it's gone through and checked
off everything in its to-do list. The
phases, the product review sub-agent,
and then the self-improvement phase is
checked off. And you can see it's given
the results of the personal CRM build,
the validation where it evaluated
itself, the feedback that got
incorporated, and then finally the
self-improvement. And the satisfying
thing about this is that you can see how
the efforts that we put in to harness
engineering have paid off. We can see
how they've been reflected in what it
actually did. We had started out with a
simple five-step process. This is what
we have now in process.md. It's
significantly built out. The process now
has an extra item at the beginning about
reading all the documentation carefully
at the beginning including the
improvement file and then we've got like
a playbook with learnings from previous
runs, architecture recipe that worked,
verification loop, unit tests are
necessary but not sufficient and review
and feedback. So there's lots of copious
notes. It's written for itself to guide
itself so that it has an improved
process next time based on what it
learned. But I'm interested to see if
it's actually been able to update the
way that it improves. If it's done some
recursive self-improvement in a
meaningful useful way. So let's look at
this file and see what it's done. So
this part here looks similar to what we
had before but it has added a new
section. How to self-improve
effectively, meta-learnings.
Do the reflection in this structured
way. All right, let's see what it came
up with. It says categorize every
learning before writing it down. That
seems very reasonable. It's got record
the detection method, write them as
executable instructions, interesting.
Prune, distinguish durable from project
improvements, close the loop by reading
it once you've written, that's great.
And then a specific tool quirk. Before
you're sure that the app is broken,
reproduce it with real user events.
Fascinating. These seem like they are
legit self-improvement learnings. Now
obviously I don't want to over-dwell on
recursive self-improvement. It's a nice
feature but it's just one of many
aspects of Harness engineering that we
put into practice and it allowed us to
get what I would say is the best CRM
that I've built so far in many times of
doing this. So I think we've done well
and I think it's a direct consequence of
the effort we put in as part of Harness
engineering. And you should try doing
some Harness engineering yourself.
There'll be instructions in the
description below to bring up this repo,
play around with it, get it to build you
a CRM and I hope it's as gorgeous as my
one right here. This is really nice, and
you can also just use this one if you'd
like a nice personal CRM. You'll find
details below as well. It's really
great. Check this out. If I come here
and I move something, I get a little
toast down here telling me that it's
moved, and then two toasts like that.
It's just great. There's so much
functionality here. So, I hope you like
the CRM, and I hope you enjoyed this
video. And if so, please do like and
subscribe. That's how I know you're
really there and you want me to make
more of these, and I will. And I hope to
see you very soon for another video.